ALEY- QabrchmounRemhala, Near Sanawbar Fuel Station Aridi Bldg, 2nd Floor

ZOUHEIR JABER PROPERTY

MOBILE 961-70-890931

E-MAIL: normawehbeh@gmail.com

NORMA FAREED WEHBEH

Personal Information

Place and Date of Birth: Bennay, February 10TH 1980

Sex: Female

Nationality: Lebanese Marital Status: Married

Objective

Get a job that best fits my qualifications and skills as considering work that deals with social communities, NGOs or any other institution implementing people's rights within their communities and local society. I am experienced for more than eighteen years working in the domain of Inclusive Education.

Languages

Arabic

English

Professional Experience

Manager, Today's Challenge Tomorrow's World (TCTW) Learning Center, Qabrchmoun-Rimhala-Aley,

August 2018-till present

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Network with schools in private and public sectors in the neighbourhood
- Contact municipalities to set a clear vision for the awareness raising sessions
- manage the service given to the learners and follow up on assessments and reports and school visits follow-up
- periodic parents meetings to collaborate and activate their role in their child's learning process
- organise and set a database of services centres and contact list for referrals
- · manage and update the Facebook page

International Learning Community (ILC), Aramoun, Aley District September 2019 till June 2020

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Manage the learning process of learners with special needs (set/modify/ adapt the curriculum/tests / homework / classwork) coordinate with the teachers and collaborate with the parents)
- · Sign agreements with the parents about the learning process of their children
- Set Individualised Educational Plans (IEP) and conduct IEP meetings with the parents
- Meet and or Call regularly the parents to assign roles and cooperate
- · Coordinate weekly with teachers to follow up based on class observation
- Maintain follow-up with specialists to ensure the inclusion plan of the learner is functioning well
- Meet weekly with coordinators in school to maintain constructive follow-up of ongoing tasks

Consultant, Sama for Development, Saida, March 2018

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Detailed work plan covering the training and coaching sessions
- Training parents on academics and behavioural issues using interactive methods
- · Training documentation including pre and post tests

- Training report
- Coaching report

Consultant, IRC, Beirut, December 2017

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Detailed work plan covering the period from the start of the consultancy until December 31st 2017
- · Documentation of assessment activities, consolidated assessment brief
- Minutes of meetings
- Training documentation, including pre- and post-tests.
- · Training package finalised
- Final report outlining the progress of activities, challenges encountered, lessons learned, and recommendations for the way forward.

Consultant, Diakonia, Beirut, August 2017

RESPONSIBILITIES

- · conduct phone calls to beneficiaries
- · review recorded tapes
- · write satisfactory survey report

Special Education Coordinator, Heritage College, Beirut from September 2014 - Sept. 2018

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Manage the learning process of transition class (set the curriculum, coordinate with the teachers, organise educational field trips, collaborate with the parents)
- · Coordinate and assists special needs educators working in inclusive regular classes
- Assist in coordinating, developing, monitoring and evaluating the effectiveness of the IEP for each student with special needs
- Participate in team work and meetings and workshops in order to improve inclusion of the learners
- Meet and or Call regularly with parents to assign roles and cooperate
- · Coordinate weekly with teachers to follow up based on class observation
- Maintain follow-up with specialists in school and outside to ensure the inclusion plan of the learner
- Meet weekly with coordinators in school to maintain constructive follow-up of ongoing tasks

Special Education Coordinator (K-12) in the Youth Association of the Blind, Beirut from February 2013-August 2014

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Coordinate and assists special needs educators working in inclusive regular primary schools
- Assist in coordinating, developing, monitoring and evaluating the effectiveness of the IEP for each student with special needs.
- Monitor the inclusion of students with disabilities in regular schools in different areas in Lebanon.
- Perform educational assessment of students with special needs.
- Participate in team work, in meetings, workshops or conferences directly related to the inclusion of students with disabilities in regular primary schools.
- Supervise, assign, coordinate and participate in the work of the centralized office.

Special Educator in the Early Intervention Unit, Disability Program, Relief and Support Services Department, UNRWA (Saida) from February 2012 to June 2012

RESPONSIBILITIES

assesses the needs of each child referred by local KGs/ Institution and local schools;

- develops an IEP stating each child's present level of functioning, objectives to meet each child's needs, methods/materials used to meet those objectives, and procedures for determining objectives;
- assists learning support teachers/community workers or KGs teachers to manage the students within their classroom in order to assure a conductive learning environment that is safe and secure for all students;
- establishes and maintains effective service relationships with parents;
- completes applications in consultation with parents, team members and other teachers and make recommendations for resource allocations and access to services;
- advises teachers in KGs on classroom strategies to support a child with disability transitioning into school;
- develops and implements, either individually or as a member of a team, inclusive programs by working collaboratively with parents, KG teachers/educators and other professionals;
- works effectively with children and young people across a diverse range of settings and circumstances;
- supports the development of community and based special education provisions and networks as required;
- observes, evaluates, and prepares reports on progress of students mainstreamed within local KGs; and
- maintains accurate service provision records and files

Manager Assistant at the Youth Association of the Blind, Beirut- Lebanon, June 2010 to November 2011

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Executes activities or sub-project business in the fields of education and development applying appropriate administrative methods.
- Prepare documents and Reports in English and Arabic
- Undertake regular field visits to control and monitor activity or sub-project execution.
- Conduct research on topics in the context of YAB work
- Arrange meetings and conferences including the preparation of the agenda, assembling background materials, and taking minutes
- Perform a wide variety of complex and confidential secretarial tasks
- Manage, update and provide content to the YAB website

Special Educator in the Early Intervention Unit, Disability Program, Relief & Support Services Department, UNRWA (Saida & Tyre) from June 2008 to May 2010.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Same as mentioned above.
- Conducts workshops about professional techniques used in the special education department.
- Conducts meetings with all concerned members in order to maintain the flow of work.
- Provides members with convenient consultations whenever needed.

Delegate from NGOs at the Ministry of Education, Department of Official Examinations from 2005 to 2015

RESPONSIBILITIES

- transcribe exams written in Braille format to print format
- read tests written in Braille format

Guest Speaker about low vision & learners with low vision at regular school for graduate students studying special education at Lebanese University during academic years 2015 till 2019

RESPONSILBILITIES

explain what's low vision and how to deal with people with low vision

- prepare materials & relative assessment forms needed to assess functional vision at school
- explain how to use assessment forms
- explain how to modify settings at classroom & school
- explain how to facilitate the learner's accessibility to academic & non-academic materials
- explain the history of education of learners with visual impairments
- examine learners at the end of the semester

Guest Speaker about low vision & learners with low vision at regular school for 3rd year students studying special education at University of Saint Joseph during academic years 2004 to 2011.

RESPONSILBILITIES

- explain what's low vision and how to deal with people with low vision
- prepare materials & relative assessment forms needed to assess functional vision at school
- explain how to use assessment forms
- explain how to modify settings at classroom & school
- explain how to facilitate the learner's accessibility to academic & non-academic materials
- explain the history of education of learners with visual impairments
- examine learners at the end of the semester

Instructor of Braille (Reading & Writing) for 3rd year students reading special education at University of Saint Joseph, May 2006 & May 2008

RESPONSIBILITIES

- explain the Braille format and its importance
- train learners on how to read & study Braille symbols
- examine learners at the end of the semester

Coordinator on Inclusion at the Youth Association of the Blind, Beirut- Lebanon from 2007 to 2008

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Train support educators for learners with visual impairments at regular schools on techniques and materials used by learners
- Train support educators for learners with visual impairments at regular schools on instructions and guidance to be practiced with teachers at inclusive schools
- Follow up with teachers at different regions in inclusive schools to ensure learning in a least restrictive environment
- Follow up with school principals to facilitate modification and adaptation of curricula & assessment forms
- Train adults and learners with visual impairments on using computers by acquiring needed skills about talking program first

Support Educator for Learners with Visual Impairments at Inclusive Schools, Youth Association of the Blind, Beirut- Lebanon from May 2002 till April 2008 (included National Inclusion Project)

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Provide teachers at the beginning of each academic year with a guidance session(s) about blindness and low vision & how to treat learners with visual impairments
- Coordinate with the Youth Association of the Blind and the school to provide learners with text books and needed materials in a timely manner

- Type text books referring to standards and print them out using the Braille embosser
- Prepare graph and figures needed in a textile format
- Suggest modifications & adaptations of curriculum and assessment forms whenever needed
- Provide learners with support during social inclusion situations
- Ensure that learners with visual impairments are partially to fully included in academic and non-academic activities as well
- Provide learners with needed materials and realia in the classroom during explanation (drawings, graphs, maps...etc.)
- Follow up the whole process and suggest needed therapy
- Submit weekly and monthly reports due to the learner's cycle
- Write success stories about learner with low vision who used laptop at the regular classroom

English Language Teacher for 1st & 2nd Grade Learners at Nashe Al-Saleem School; Aramoun- Aley academic year 2001- 2002

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Prepare and implement lessons
- Submit monthly reports
- Assess learners daily, weekly, and by the end of each term
- Discuss learners situations with parents and coordinator

Private Tutor from 1998 to 2000 teaching Math, Sciences, & English Language to learners at grades4 to7

Education

- Masters in Education, Notre-Dame University-Louaize, <u>In progress</u>
- Professional Management Diploma, Lifelong Learning Center, Haigazian University, Feb. 2010
- Human Resources Management Diploma, Lifelong Learning Center, Haigazian University, May 2009
- MA in Sociology (Thesis in Social Anthropology), Institute of Social Sciences, Lebanese University, Beirut 2007
- Maitrise in Sociology (Thesis in Cultural Anthropology), Institute of Social Sciences, Lebanese University, Beirut 2003
- BA in Social Sciences (Specialization, Anthropology), Institute of Social Sciences, Lebanese University, Beirut 2002

Qualifications	January 2014	Attended workshop about "Technology and inclusive Education", SESSES, Cyprus.
	June 2010	Attended workshop about "Technological Advancement & Cultural Changes and their Effects on the Future of Learning", Harvard Graduate School of Education
	Dec. 2009	Attended two days workshop about "Dance Movement Therapy" facilitated by a Palestinian NGO , Trainer: Mrs. Amber Gray
	Nov. 2009	Delegated to attend regional workshop (Netherlands- Naba'a) for 2 days: "Impediments & Difficulties facing participation of children & youth" Lebanese American University and Arab Resource Collective at Holiday

Inn, Beirut

OCpt. 2000	Modification"
Feb. 2008	Delegated to travel to South Africa (Cape Town) to attend a meeting for the officers of the World Blind Union
Dec. 2007	Delegated to share in a conference held in Jordan and make a presentation about "Role of Support Educator in Inclusive schools for students with visual impairments"
Dec 2007	Delegated to travel to Sri Lanka to attend meeting for the Asian Blind Union
Aug. 2007	Attended workshop on <i>Children's Participation</i> by Save the Children UK facilitated by Nabaa
2006- 2007	Attended workshops on education and methodology in education for students with different physical and mental disabilities prepared by National Inclusion Project
Feb. 2007	Delegated to travel to Canada to attend a meeting for the World Blind Union
March 2007	Delegated to travel to India to attend a meeting for the Asian Blind Union
Winter 2006	Attended a 15 hours training session for trainers on Braille Lite (Electronic note taker for students with visual disabilities) at MeDialog S.A.L.
August 2005	Attended the course "Effective Teaching and Evaluation" at Haigazian
August 2005 Fall 2005	University Attended the course "Classroom Dynamics" at Haigazian University Attended workshop about "Experience in Inclusion in Arabic Countries" Yemen
Fall 2004 Fall 2004	Attended the course "Issues on Inclusion" at University of Saint Joseph Attended the course "Methods and Materials for Teaching Children with Low Vision" at University of Saint Joseph
August 2004	Attended the course "Psychology Applied to Teaching" at Haigazian University
July 2004	Participated in Session Workshop about "Positive Discipline" (Taking Supportive & Reinforcing Student Behavior- grades 1 to 6) at Haigazian University
May 2002	Participated in a 5 days training session "Training on Low Vision" by Asian Blind Union Nepal

Delegated to attend a 3 days workshop at USJ, "Behavior Management and

Interests and activities

Member in the administrative assembly of Today's Challenge Tomorrow's World (TCTW) since 2018

Member in the general assembly of the Youth Association of the Blind (YAB) since 2005 Member in the Technology Committee at the Youth Association of the Blind (YAB) 2013 Acting, Reading

Painting: attended several sessions for two years (Instructor: Hasan Yatim) and shared in local exhibitions.

Research: especially researches that serve learners and develop all concerned institutions like schools and NGOs that support teaching for all. I am also interested in researches that are conducted to study communities in general and particularly minorities.

References

Provided upon request.

Sept. 2008